Guide to the J. Ari Kane-Demaios' male erotic films, circa 1960-1970.
Kane-Demaios', J. Ari male erotic films
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
J. Ari Kane-Demaios' male erotic films, circa 1960-1970.
7780
Kane-Demaios, J. Ari,
1 cubic foot of films;
Movie film
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Films collected by J. Ari Kane with primarily male homosexual erotic pornography.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
J. Ari Kane, also known as Ariadne Kane and published under the name J. Ari Kane-Demaios, was born Joseph DeMaios in New York on 12 January 1936. In 1958 he received a Bachelor of Science in Biophysics, Mathematics and Chemistry at City College, New York and undertook graduate work in biophysics at New York University and University of Buffalo. He holds a doctorate of Education from Institute for Advanced Study of Sexuality and is an assistant professor of sexology at the Institute for the Advanced Study of Human Sexuality in San Francisco. He also runs Theseus Counseling Services which specializes in gender issues.
Interested in cross-dressing and supporting alternative gender expression, in 1975, Kane founded the Human Outreach and Achievement Institute, an organization dedicated to public education and to working with the health professionals who serve the community. In the early 1980s it was renamed the Outreach Institute for Gender Studies (OIGS) and its Board of Directors was established. The purpose of OIGS is "to advance the understanding of gender identity and role development with a special focus on alternative gender lifestyles." OIGS published the Outreach Newsletter and the Journal of Gender Studies (1991-1995), and provides educational materials to the public, to TV/TS individuals and groups, and to medical professionals.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Films collected by J. Ari Kane with primarily male homosexual erotic pornography.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Kane-Demaios, J. Ari,
Subjects:
Homosexuality.; Gay men.; Gay pornography.
Form and Genre Terms:
Erotica.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Ari Kane/Joseph DeMaios records, 1943-2003, are at the University of Victoria Archives.
NOTES
Collecting Program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- 2 Boys, 1 Star, 879 (Box 1)
- 2 Boys, Fucking, 880 (Box 1)
- 2 Guys On Stairway, 881 (Box 1)
- 2 in Bushes, 882 (Box 1)
- 2 Males, 883 (Box 1)
- 2 on Hillside, 884 (Box 1)
- 2 Young Ones, 885 (Box 1)
- 3-Some with Joe Markhum, 886 (Box 1)
- 3 at Swimming Pool, 887 (Box 1)
- 3-Way, Black Tee Shirt, 888 (Box 1)
- 3 Way in Desert, 889 (Box 1)
- Beard, 890 (Box 1)
- Bill Eld, 891 (Box 1)
- Black Backdrop with Bill Harris, 892 (Box 1)
- Black Backdrop with Bill Harris-Oral, 894 (Box 1)
- Blow Job in Woods, 894 (Box 1)
- Blue Streak, 1982; 895 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Brentwood, Bijou Bideo Sales
  Director(s): Jack Travis
  Performer(s): Cliff, Craig, Bill Baxter, Case Edwards
- Card Shark, 896 (Box 1)
- Cock on Delivery: Checking His Route, 1977; 897 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Mustang Productions
  Performer(s): Dale Morgan, Jack Wrangler, Gavin
- Come 'N Leather, 1972; 898 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Falcon Studios
  Performer(s):Jack Vaughn; Dick (John Davis)
- Creaming in the Shower, 1970; 899 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Spectra
- Daisies Don't Always Grow on Chains, 1971; 900 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Bill Eld, Jim Cassidy, Sandy Douglas
- Does Not Feed, 901 (Box 1)
- The Expert, 902 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Bob, Dan
- Football, 903 (Box 1)
- Football Team Part I, 904 (Box 1)
- Football Team Part II, 905 (Box 1)
- Football Team Part III, 906 (Box 1)
- Glory Hole, 907 (Box 1)
- Glory Hole I, 908 (Box 1)
- Groupie, 909 (Box 1)
- Horny Hustlers (Pretty Boy), 1972; 910 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Dimension Films
  Performer(s): Duke Benson, Jake Dillon
- The Hot Line, 911 (Box 1)
- John Walt Holmes, 912 (Box 1)
- Junior Cadets: Chemistry Lesson, 1976; 913 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Mustang Studios
  Performer(s): Bob, John, Mark
- Kinks: Liquid Plumber, 1976; 914 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): XXX, Inc.
- Knights of the Night: A Hard Lesson, 1975; 915 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Bob Anthony Studio
- Life in the Big City (Pretty Boy), 916 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Quality Films
  Performer(s): Jean Cardin
- Manhandler, 1971; 917 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Lux Publications
- Markhum, 918 (Box 1)
- Markhum, 919 (Box 1)
- Mark and Philip, 920 (Box 1)
- Monte, 921 (Box 1)
- My First Love, 1972; 922 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Telstar Productions
  Performer(s): Dave Rogers, Walt Grayson, Steve
- The North 40, 1974; 923 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Tommy, Ken
- The Paperboy and Mr. Egan, 1975; 924 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Brentwood
  Performer(s): David, Mr. Egan
- Pleasure Point Part II, 1975; 925 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Joe Markhum, Chris Christy, Tim Christy
- Queer Ball, 926 (Box 1)
- Sailboat Part I, 927 (Box 1)
- San Francisco Stud, 928 (Box 1)
- Scandia, 1971; 929 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Scandia
  Performer(s): Bill, Michael, Roger, Ron
- School's Out, 1986; 930 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Bob, Bob, Chris Christy, Frank, jack, Rusty, Ted, Terry, Tim Christy
- Wild Holidays IV, 1971; 931 (Box 1)
- Young Stallions: Screw My Buddy, 1974; 932 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): P.M. Productions
- Not Labeled, 933 (Box 1)
- Not Labeled, 934 (Box 1)
- Not Labeled, 935 (Box 1)
- Not Labeled, 936 (Box 1)
- 3 in Jail, 937 (Box 1)
- The Best of Cum NO. 61, 938 (Box 1)
- Canadian Burt, 939 (Box 1)
- Horse: Com'n' Get it, 1978; 940 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Jack Egan
- Horse: Golden Stream, 1976; 941 (Box 1)
- Horse: Hot Assed Cocksuckers From the Hills, 1977; 942 (Box 1)
- Interludes: Joe and Bill, 1981; 943 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Le Salon VIdeo
  Performer(s): Joe, Bill
- Incessant Sex, 1972; 944 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Larry Vaughan,, Parris Mitchell
- Jocks: Football, 1976; 945 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Andy Blake, Kevin Warren, Billy Nordstrom
- Jocks: Pinning a Stud, 1976; 946 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Biff Addison, Mike Savage, jerry Douglas
- Jocks: Scoring a Basket, 1976; 947 (Box 1)
  Performer(s): Don Lawson, Ron Cameron
- Jogger and Coach, 948 (Box 1)
- Ram, 949 (Box 1)
- Ranch Hands, 950 (Box 1)
  Producer(s):
  Performer(s): Markhum
- Salt and Pepper (From "Boys in the Sand"), 951 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Poolemar Productions
  Director(s): Wakefield Poole
- Stable Stud, 952 (Box 1)
  Producer(s): Nova Films
  Performer(s): Carl Holt, Ted Roberts
- Teacher and Student, 953 (Box 1)
- Not Labeled, 954 (Box 1)